Guide to the Cleanth Brooks Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1928-86; Series II; 26.5; (64 boxes)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - Essays and Lectures: Subjects
      - Poetry
        - "She Dwelt Among the Untrodden Ways"
          - Draft, typescript, corrected, photocopy [2 copies], n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1547)
        - "Some Scattered Observations on Poetry in a Discouraging Time holograph, typescript and photocopy, corrected, 1981 (Box 77, Folder 1548)
        - "Two Garden Poems": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1549)
        - Trinity College lectures
          See: Box 76, folders 1516-29
        - Unidentified draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1550)
        - Unidentified draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1551)
        - Unidentified draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1552)
        - Unidentified draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1553)
      - Religion
        - Bryan College lectures
          See: Box 77, folders 1555-59 and Box 78, folders 1571-72
        - "Christian Myth and the Symbolist Poets": typescript carbon, corrected (Box 77, Folder 1554)
        - "Christianity and Literature "
          - Draft A, typescript, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1555)
          - Draft A, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1556)
          - Draft B, typescript, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1557)
          - Draft B, typescript, photocopy [enlargement], copy I, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1558)
          - Draft B, typescript, photocopy [enlargement], copy II, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1559)
        - "The Christianity of Modernism"
          See: Box 78, folders 1576-77
        - "The Church in a Secular Age"
          - Outline, research notes, and draft fragments (Box 77, Folder 1560)
          - Draft A, holograph, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1561)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1562)
          - Draft C, typescript, corrected, and photocopies (Box 78, Folder 1563)
        - "The College Man and the Christian Faith": typescript, corrected, 1953 (Box 78, Folder 1564)
        - "Faulkner's Spiritual and Ethical Values"
          See: Box 67, folder 1260
        - "Faulkner's Ultimate Values"
          See: Box 68, folders 1268-69
        - "Faulkner's Vision of Good and Evil"
          See: Box 68, folders 1270-72
        - "God, Gallup, and the Episcopalians"
          - Draft, typescript, ca. 1981 (Box 78, Folder 1565)
          - Draft, typescript, photocopy, corrected, ca. 1981 (Box 78, Folder 1566)
          - Printed version, 1981 (Box 78, Folder 1567)
          - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 78, Folder 1568)
          - Abstract, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 1569)
        - "Literature and Belief: The Implications of an Organic Theory of Poetry"
          See: Box 76, folder 1537
        - "Literature and Religion": typescript and carbon, 1965 Jun 13 (Box 78, Folder 1570)
        - "Literature As an Adjunct to Religion"
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 1571)
          - Draft B, typescript, 1982 Apr (Box 78, Folder 1572)
        - "Man and Nature": typescript, corrected (Box 78, Folder 1573)
        - "Our Holy Numbskulls"
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 1574)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 1575)
        - "A Plea to the Protestant Churches"
          - Draft, typescript, corrected [2 copies], n.d. (Box 78, Folder 1576)
          - Dust jacket for Who Owns America?: A New Declaration of Independence, ed. by Herbert Agar and Allen Tate, in which the above essay appeared (Box 78, Folder 1577)
        - "Prayer Book"
          - Research notes, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 1578)
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 1579)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 1580)
        - "Prayer Book Revision: Literary Style": typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 1581)
        - "Religion and Literature"
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 1582)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, photocopy, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 1583)
          - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 1584)
          - Draft D, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 1585)
          - Draft E, typescript, corrected, photocopy, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 1586)
          - Draft F, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 1587)
          - Draft G, typescript, corrected, photocopy [2 copies], n.d. (Box 78, Folder 1588)
        - "Religion and the South": notes (Box 78, Folder 1589)
        - "The Return to Theology": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 1590)
        - "Telling It Like It Is In the Tower of Babel": typescript, photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 1591)
        - "Walker Percy and Modern Gnosticism"
          See: Box 70, folder 1345-46
        - Unidentified draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 1592)
      - Southern Literature and Culture
        "The American South and Yeat's Ireland"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1593)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, photocopy, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1594)
        - Draft C, typescript, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1595)
        - Draft D, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1596)
        - Page proofs, corrected, photocopy, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1597)
        - "The Culture of the South and the Southern Sense of History"
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1598)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1599)
        - "The Current State of Southern Letters"
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1600)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1601)
        - "Eudora Welty and the Southern Idiom"
          See: Box 71, folder 1364
        - "The Importance of 'Place' in Southern Literature"
          - Draft A, typescript, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1602)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1603)
          - Draft C, typescript, corrected, photocopy, copy I, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1604)
          - Draft C, typescript, corrected, photocopy, copy II, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1605)
          - Draft D, typescript, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1606)
          - Draft D, typescript, photocopy [enlargement], n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1607)
        - Lamar Memorial lectures
          See: Box 35, folders 660-70
        - "The Past Alive in the Present"
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1608)
          - Draft B, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1609)
          - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1610)
          - Draft fragments, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1611)
        - "The 'Provincial' Writer: His Handicaps and His Advantages": typescript, corrected (Box 79, Folder 1612)
        - "Religion and the South"
          See: Box 78, folder 1589
        - "The South in Transition"
          - Outline, holograph, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1613)
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected, photocopy, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1614)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1615)
        - "Southern Literature: The Past History, and the Timeless": outline, holograph (Box 79, Folder 1616)
        - "The Southernness of Walker Percy"
          See: Box 70, folders 1343-44
        - "T. S. Eliot and the American South"
          See: Box 66, folders 1213-17
        - "What Is Southern Literature"
          - Early draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1617)
          - Later draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1618)
          - Draft fragments, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1619)
          - Correspondence, 1981-82, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1620)
        - "William Faulkner--Culture Hero for the Region"
          See: Box 69, folders 1302-03
        - Unidentified draft, holograph, corrected, 1985 Dec (Box 79, Folder 1621)
      - Printed Material
        - Lecture programs, schedules, flyers, etc., 1949-83, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1622)
        - Newspaper clippings, 1937-83, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1623-26)
    - Sermons
      - Typescript, corrected, 1948-59 (Box 80, Folder 1627)
    - Speeches
      - "International Cultural Exchange": holograph, 1964 Oct 30 (Box 80, Folder 1628)
      - "Marshall Plan Fellows at Lancaster House": typescript, corrected, 1966 May 7 (Box 80, Folder 1629)
      - "Response for the Honoreds at the Honorary Degree Ceremonies at the University of Exeter": typescript, photocopy, 1966 (Box 80, Folder 1630)
      - "Talk at St. Paul's School": notes, typescript, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1631)
      - Unidentified: notes, holograph, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1632)
    - Book reviews
      - Bowra, C. M., The Romantic Imagination: typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1633)
      - Coburn, Kathleen, In Pursuit of Coleridge: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1634)
      - Faulkner, William, Flags in the Dust: typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1635)
      - Fogle, Richard, The Imagery of Keats and Shelley: typescript carbon (Box 80, Folder 1636)
      - Frye, Northrup, The Anatomy of Criticism: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1637)
      - Housman, A. E., The Name and Nature of Poetry: printed version, 1933 (Box 80, Folder 1638)
      - Kazin, Alfred, The Inmost Leaf: printed version, annotated, 1955 Nov 6 (Box 80, Folder 1639)
      - Lovejoy, Arthur O., Essays in the History of Ideas: typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 80, Folder 1640)
      - Lucas, F. L., The Decline and Fall of the Romantic Ideal: typescript, corrected, and carbon (Box 80, Folder 1641)
      - Olney, James, The Rhizome and the Flower: typescript, corrected (Box 80, Folder 1642)
      - Spears, Monroe, Dionysus and the City: typescript carbon, corrected (Box 80, Folder 1643)
      - Spring Anthology: typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1644)
      - Tate, Allen
        - Reason in Madness: typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1645)
        - The Winter Sea: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1646)
      - Unger, Leonard, Eliot's Compound Ghost: Influence and Confluence: typescript, corrected, 1986 (Box 80, Folder 1647)
      - Wade, Allan, ed., The Letters of W. B. Yeats: typescript, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1648)
      - Unidentified: typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1649)
    - Radio scripts
      - Unidentified: typescript carbon, corrected, 1939 Jun 26 (Box 80, Folder 1650)
      - Unidentified: typescript carbon, corrected, 1951 Sep 30 (Box 80, Folder 1651)
    - Radio program reviews
      - Johnson, Reid B. and Frederic D. Grab, "A Tribute to Ezra Pound": typescript, corrected (Box 80, Folder 1652)
    - Letters to the Editor
      - Letters to the editor, 1936-83, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1653)
- Classroom Material, 1949-75; Series III; 1; (2 boxes)
  Series III, Classroom Material (Boxes 81-82), is divided into four subseries, Reserve Lists, Classroom Lists, Examinations, and Gradebooks. Each subseries is arranged numerically according to course number.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Examinations and Gradebooks, in boxes 81a and 82, are restricted until January 1, 2063.
  - RESERVE LISTS
    - English 71, 1966-69, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 1654)
    - English 150, 1950-57, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 1655)
    - English 160, 1963-67, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 1656)
  - CLASSROOM LISTS
    - English 71: course description and syllabus, 1963-64 (Box 81, Folder 1657)
    - English 71: transcription of classroom lectures
      - No. 1, 1963 Feb 4 (Box 81, Folder 1658)
      - No. 2, 1963 Feb 6 (Box 81, Folder 1659)
      - No. 3, 1963 Feb 8 (Box 81, Folder 1660)
      - No. 4, 1963 Feb 11 (Box 81, Folder 1661)
      - No. 5, 1963 Feb 13 (Box 81, Folder 1662)
  - EXAMINATIONS
    - English 71, 1971-75, n.d. (Box 81a, Folder 1663)
      Restricted until January 1, 2063. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - GRADEBOOKS
    - English 15, 1951-52, n.d. (Box 81a, Folder 1664)
      These materials are restricted from use until January 1, 2063. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
    - English 25 and 27, 1953-55, n.d. (Box 81a, Folder 1665)
    - English 54, 1958-59 (Box 81a, Folder 1666)
    - English 71, 1949-58 (Box 81a, Folder 1667-68)
    - English 71, 1959-73, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 1669-71)
    - English 72, 1957 (Box 82, Folder 1672)
    - English 88, 1963 (Box 82, Folder 1673)
    - English 109, 1963 (Box 82, Folder 1674)
    - English 150, 1961-67 (Box 82, Folder 1675-77)
    - English 150 and 160, 1967-73 (Box 82, Folder 1676)
    - English 152, 1955-63 (Box 82, Folder 1679)
    - English 160, 1947-74 (Box 82, Folder 1680-82)
    - Drama 126, 1955-56 (Box 82, Folder 1683)
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 1684)
- Professional Papers, 1940-86; Series IV; 2; (5 boxes)
  Series IV, Professional Papers (Boxes 83-87), is divided into five subseries, Cultural Attaché Material; Visiting Professorships; Conferences, Symposia, Seminars, Trips, etc.; Interviews; and Subject Files. These materials are ordered according to a combination of alphabetical, hierarchical, and chronological arrangements.
  - CULTURAL ATTACHÉ MATERIAL
    - Correspondence
      - "A" general, 1965-70 (Box 83, Folder 1685)
      - "B" general, 1964-65 (Box 83, Folder 1686)
      - Bode, Carl, 1964-70 (Box 83, Folder 1687)
      - Brooks, Edith Amy Blanchard ("Tinkum"), 1963 Dec 12 (Box 83, Folder 1688)
      - "C" general, 1964-66 (Box 83, Folder 1689)
      - Clark, William L., 1964 (Box 83, Folder 1690)
      - "D" general, 1964-65 (Box 83, Folder 1691)
      - "E" general, 1964 (Box 83, Folder 1692)
      - "F" general, 1964-69 (Box 83, Folder 1693)
      - Friends of Friendless Churches, 1964-69 (Box 83, Folder 1694)
      - "G" general, 1964-77 (Box 83, Folder 1695)
      - "H" general, 1966 (Box 83, Folder 1696)
      - "J" general, 1965-66 (Box 83, Folder 1697)
      - "K" general, 1964 (Box 83, Folder 1698)
      - "L" general, 1964-69 (Box 83, Folder 1699)
      - Lambert, Jack, 1965-66 (Box 83, Folder 1700)
      - Leicester University Press, 1966-67 (Box 83, Folder 1701)
      - "M" general, 1964-70 (Box 83, Folder 1702)
      - Mason, Francis, 1964-65 (Box 83, Folder 1703)
      - Novick, Jerome L., 1963-64 (Box 83, Folder 1704)
      - "O" general, 1963-66 (Box 83, Folder 1705)
      - "P" general, 1965-69 (Box 83, Folder 1706)
      - "R" general, 1964-66 (Box 83, Folder 1707)
      - "S" general, 1964-66 (Box 83, Folder 1708)
      - "T" general, 1965-66 (Box 83, Folder 1709)
      - U. S. Advisory Commission on International Education and Cultural Affairs, 1960-69 (Box 83, Folder 1710-12)
      - U. S. Department of State, 1957-70 (Box 83, Folder 1713)
      - U. S. I. A., 1955-71 (Box 83, Folder 1714)
      - U. S. I. S., 1964-70 (Box 83, Folder 1715)
      - "W" general, 1964-69 (Box 83, Folder 1716)
      - Weld, W. E., Jr., 1966-70 (Box 83, Folder 1717)
      - Winks, Robin, 1969-70 (Box 83, Folder 1718)
      - "Y" general, 1965-66 (Box 83, Folder 1719)
      - "Z" general, 1964 (Box 83, Folder 1720)
      - Unidentified, 1964-69 (Box 83, Folder 1721)
    - Invitations, 1964-71, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 1722-26)
    - Guest lists and seating charts, 1964-66 (Box 84, Folder 1727)
    - Programs, 1961-66 (Box 84, Folder 1728-31)
    - Schedules and itineraries, 1964-66 (Box 84, Folder 1732)
    - Job application material, 1964 (Box 84, Folder 1733)
    - Memorandum on the post of cultural attaché, 1966 (Box 84, Folder 1734)
    - Debriefing, 1966 Jun (Box 84, Folder 1735)
    - Notes, [1964-66] (Box 84, Folder 1736)
    - Lecture, [1964-66] (Box 84, Folder 1737)
    - Miscellaneous papers, [1964-66] (Box 84, Folder 1738)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1964-66 (Box 84, Folder 1739)
      See also: Box 94, folder 1974
      See also: Box 96, folder 2004
  - VISITING PROFESSORSHIPS
    - Kenyon College
      - Handbooks, 1948 (Box 85, Folder 1740)
    - Millsaps College
      - Programs: "The Inauguration of the Eudora Welty Chair in Southern Studies", 1983 Jan 20 (Box 85, Folder 1741)
      - Lectures: "The Importance of 'Place' in Southern Literature": printed version, 1983 Jan 20 (Box 85, Folder 1742)
      - Gradebooks, 1983 (Box 85, Folder 1743)
        [These are restricted from use until January 1, 2058]
      - Newspaper clippings, 1983 (Box 85, Folder 1744)
    - Tulane University
      - Miscellaneous, 1976, n.d. (Box 85, Folder 1745)
    - University of North Carolina
      - Newspaper clippings, 1977 (Box 85, Folder 1746)
    - University of Tennessee
      - Newspaper clippings, 1978 (Box 85, Folder 1747)
  - CONFERENCES, SYMPOSIA, SEMINARS, TRIPS, ETC.
    - Conference on Southern Literature, 1981 May (Box 85, Folder 1748)
    - England, Trip to, 1984-85 (Box 85, Folder 1749)
    - Europe, Trip to, 1967 Jun (Box 85, Folder 1750)
    - Faulkner Seminar at West Point, 1981-86 (Box 85, Folder 1751)
    - Japanese Faulkner Conference, 1981-86 (Box 85, Folder 1752-54)
      See also: Box 94, folders 1977-78
    - Jordan and Syria, Trip to, 1984 (Box 85, Folder 1755-57)
      See also: Box 94, folder 1979
    - Miami Book Fair International, 1985 (Box 85, Folder 1758)
    - Miami University (Oxford, Ohio), Trip to, 1985 (Box 85, Folder 1759)
    - Princeton Inn Conference, 1951-54 (Box 85, Folder 1760-61)
    - Russia, Trip to, 1986 Feb-Apr (Box 85, Folder 1762)
    - Savannah, Trip to, 1984-85 (Box 85, Folder 1763)
    - Southern Letters & Modern Literature: A National Literary Conference, 1984-85 (Box 86, Folder 1764-65)
    - Tennessee Homecoming '86 Literary Festival, 1986 (Box 86, Folder 1766)
    - Thirteenth Conference in Theology, Trinity College, Hartford, Connecticut, 1963 Jun 14-20 (Box 86, Folder 1767)
    - United States Air Force Academy, Trip to (Box 86, Folder 1768)
    - Conference programs, 1940-78, n.d. (Box 86, Folder 1769-73)
  - INTERVIEWS
    - Transcription of interview with Cleanth Brooks by anonymous for Fresh Fruit, weekly newspaper pub. by Brown University, Providence, R. I.: printed version, parts I & II, 1975 Jan-Feb (Box 86, Folder 1774)
    - Transcription of interview with Cleanth Brooks by Wroy Herbert for the American Association for the Advancement of the Humanities, Washington, D. C.: typescript, cassettes I-III, 1981 Oct (Box 86, Folder 1775-77)
      See also: Box 96, folders 2005-07
    - Transcription of interview with Cleanth Brooks by Charles GaNun for Wilbraham Academy Yearbook, Wilbraham, Mass.: printed version, 1960 Apr 12 (Box 86, Folder 1778)
    - Transcription of radio interview with Cleanth Brooks by Bernard Mullins for "Yale Interprets the News," WTIC-Hartford, Conn.: typescript carbon, corrected, 1949 Mar 6 (Box 86, Folder 1779)
    - Transcription of radio interview with Cleanth Brooks and Eudora Welty by Bernard Mullins for "Yale Reports," WTIC-Hartford, Conn.: typescript, mimeograph, 1963 May 26 (Box 86, Folder 1780)
  - SUBJECT FILES
    - Agrarian Movement
      See: Box 93, folder 1970
    - Auden, W. H., 1962 Mar 13 (Box 87, Folder 1781)
    - Baldwin, James, 1964 (Box 87, Folder 1782)
    - The Bollingen Prize in Poetry, 1949-50 (Box 87, Folder 1783)
    - Eliot, T. S., 1948-86 (Box 87, Folder 1784)
    - Faulkner, William, 1985 (Box 87, Folder 1785)
    - Foundation for the Arts, Religion and Culture, 1967-68, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 1786)
    - Frost, Robert, 1974 Oct 11 (Box 87, Folder 1787)
    - The Fugitives, 1959 (Box 87, Folder 1788)
    - Hayes, Harold R., n.d. (Box 87, Folder 1789)
    - Jackson, Laura (Riding), 1972 (Box 87, Folder 1790)
    - The Kenyon Review, 1970 Mar 9 (Box 87, Folder 1791)
    - Kroll, Judith, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 1792)
    - Lawrence, David Herbert, 1964 Oct 29 (Box 87, Folder 1793)
    - Literary criticism, 1983 May 27 (Box 87, Folder 1794)
    - McLuhan, Marshall, 1949-67 (Box 87, Folder 1795)
    - Percy, Walker, 1974 (Box 87, Folder 1796)
    - Pornography, 1985 (Box 87, Folder 1797)
    - Porter, Katherine Anne
      - Festschrift, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 1798)
      - "In memoriam" by Cleanth Brooks, 1980 (Box 87, Folder 1799)
      - Miscellaneous, 1950-82, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 1800)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1947-84 (Box 87, Folder 1801)
    - Ransom, John Crowe, 1948, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 1802)
    - Recommendations, Letters of
      - "A" - "C", 1976-86, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 1803)
      - "D" - "K", 1981-82, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 1804)
      - "L" - "S", 1975-86, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 1805)
      - "T" - "W", unidentified, 1982-85, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 1806)
    - Religion, 1973 May 25 (Box 87, Folder 1807)
    - Richards, I. A., 1959 Jul 10 (Box 87, Folder 1808)
    - The Southern Review, 1952-85, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 1809)
    - Voegelin, Eric, 1984-85, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 1810)
    - Warren, Robert Penn
      - Departure from LSU for University of Minnesota, 1942 May 9 (Box 87, Folder 1811)
      - Appointment as Professor of Playwriting, Department of Drama, Yale University, 1951 Apr (Box 87, Folder 1812)
      - General, 1951-86, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 1813)
      - Winner of Bollingen Prize in Poetry, 1967 Feb (Box 87, Folder 1814)
      - Winner of Connecticut Arts Award [including presentation speech by Cleanth Brooks], 1980 (Box 87, Folder 1815)
        See also: Box 94, folder 1981
    - Wellek, René, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 1816)
    - Welty, Eudora, 1972 May 21 (Box 87, Folder 1817)
    - White House Library: selection of book titles, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 1818)
    - Woodward, Glenn, 1982 Jun 5 (Box 87, Folder 1819)
    - Miscellaneous, 1971, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 1820)
- Writings of Others, 1943-86; Series V; 1; (2 boxes)
  Series V, Writings of Others Boxes 88-89), is divided into three subseries, Works on Brooks, Robert Penn Warren, and Miscellany. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically according to author and thereunder according to title.
  - WORKS ON BROOKS
    - Pole, Davis, "Cleanth Brooks and the New Criticism": printed version, photocopy (Box 88, Folder 1821)
    - Simpson, Lewis P., ed., The Possibilities of Order: Cleanth Brooks and His Work
      - Advertisements, 1975 (Box 88, Folder 1822)
      - Book reviews, 1976-77 (Box 88, Folder 1823)
    - Tassin, Anthony, "Cleanth Brooks and New Trends in the New Criticism": typescript, mimeograph, 1967 Aug 17 (Box 88, Folder 1824)
    - Wellek, René, "Cleanth Brooks, Critic of Critics": offprint, 1974 (Box 88, Folder 1825)
    - Young, T. D., "Cleanth Brooks and Vanderbilt": typescript, corrected, 1981 Nov 5 (Box 88, Folder 1826)
  - ROBERT PENN WARREN
    - Book reviews
      - All the King's Men, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1827)
      - At Heaven's Gate, 1943 Aug 22 (Box 88, Folder 1828)
      - Band of Angels, 1955 (Box 88, Folder 1829)
      - Brother to Dragons, 1953, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1830)
      - Wilderness, 1961 Nov 8 (Box 88, Folder 1831)
    - Books
      - At Heaven's Gate: synopsis, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1832)
    - Essays
      - "Fiction: Why We Read It": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1833)
      - "A Lesson Read in American Books": printed version, 1955 Dec 11 (Box 88, Folder 1834)
      - "The Right to Knowledge": typescript, photocopy, 1954 Oct 27-30 (Box 88, Folder 1835)
      - Unidentified, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1836)
    - Lecture reviews
      - Lecture reviews, 1951-55 (Box 88, Folder 1837)
    - Lectures
      - "William Faulkner and His South": typescript, mimeograph, 1951 Mar 13 (Box 88, Folder 1838)
    - Play Programs
      - All the King's Men, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1839)
    - Play Reviews
      - All the King's Men, 1947-59 (Box 88, Folder 1840)
    - Poetry
      - "Albino-pale, half blind, his orbit revolved": typescript, corrected (Box 88, Folder 1841)